

William Wee

• Batam, Indonesia • +62 853 6383 5334

williamwee168@gmail.com

I am a motivated junior developer, changing career after many years in the recruitment and education fields. I have proficiency in React.js, a fast learner, and enjoying every bit of software development. I am looking for a position to help me grow and make me a professional developer.

Relevant Skills

• Languages and frameworks : HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Databases : MySQL

Tools : Trello, Word, GitHub, Visual Studio, Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator

• Working knowledge of : Express, MongoDB, Node.js

Personal Projects

• Color Code Generator (HTML, CSS, JavaScript). A color generator that enables user to match color and copy the code before paste into their work. **See demo and code.**

- Budget Expense (HTML, CSS, React.js, Bootstrap). Budget expenses help to track item spend by setting the
 daily amount of money. Users can edit budget amount too. See demo and code.
- Browser Dashboard (HTML, CSS, Tailwind, API). Browser dashboard is an extension for chrome browser. It
 notifies daily Bitcoin price using free API and have updated wallpaper after each page refreshing.
 See demo and code.
- Rental Partners (HTML, CSS, React.js, Bootstrap). A landing page to encourage user to have social network before continue for further relationship. **See demo and code.**

Work Experience

Nov 2021 - Present ICAN Education Consultant Indonesia English TOEFL / IELTS Instructor (Part-time)

- Defined, designed, implemented the TOEFL / IELTS course syllabus in accordance to 20 students' proficiency level each batch.
- Assessed students' ability, executing lesson plans, and enhancing students' knowledge in the academic areas.
- Prepared resources for students' lesson plans, and classroom activities, in line with the objectives of the program.

Nov 2021 - Present LearnLight UK Bahasa Indonesia / English Trainer (Part-time)

- Developed coursework materials includes handouts, essays, and additional homework assignments.
- Evaluated learners' performances, including making note of how well students participate in the discussion.
- Acted as a consultant for foreign expatriates, which can entail local business and networking.

Aug 2020 - Nov 2021 Glints Global Intra Talenta Singapore Talent Manager

- Determined talent acquisition strategies and hiring plans.
- Assessed talent of prospective candidates in the healthcare, business, and construction industries.
- Worked with partner organization to devise talent and measured hired employees' performance on behalf of client.

Aug 2019 - Aug 2020 PT Dehong Paper Industry China Human Resources Generalist

- Developed human management guidelines and departmental procedure standards in Chinese and Bahasa Indonesia.
- Performed recruitment, interview, selection, recruiting budget, and staff retention system.
- Managed employees' salary, insurance, personal income tax, and medical benefits for more than 150 employees.

Education

Feb 2021 - Feb 2022 Scrimba Front End Web Development Bootcamp
 Aug 2008 - Sep 2020 London School of Economics BSc in Accounting and Finance
 Jan 2006 - Jun 2007 SIM Global Education Dip in Management